Sam Cullen



(+353) 85 228 2890



samcull2000@gmail.com



https://github.com/SamCull



https://www.linkedin.com/in/sam-cullen-489a46221



https://samcullen.netlify.app/

Personal Summary

Graduated with BSc degree in Software Development at SETU Carlow and pursuing my honours degree in my final year. Now seeking the opportunity to begin work and to learn and gain new skills within a workplace. Since my school years, I've had a deep interest in computers and software development and from then I knew that this was where I would build my education and wanted to make a career out of something I'd enjoy. I've been playing rugby since I was young and played on an international level in Rugby League for 4+ years. With this sporting background, I am very comfortable with collaborating with a team and being well-driven to perform to the best standard when completing key tasks.

I would love to speak further with you about this position so please feel free to contact me with any of the details provided above.

Education

BSc Software Development, SETU Carlow 2019 - Present

Secondary School, St Marys Knockbeg College, Carlow 2013 - 2019

Work Experience

Supermacs

July 2023 - Present

- Working part-time during college and performing well in a fast working environment
- Working well and getting along with coworkers and managers, outperforming expectations for the short time I have been here

Sales Assistant Top Oil

August 2020 - July 2023

- Worked part-time in a fuelling station where I have helped many customers and trained 10+ staff members over the course of my time working there.
- Very good with talking to customers and making good relations with customers and fellow staff in a friendly and helpful manner.
- Do stock takes/orders when necessary and I am trained to perform manager tasks when managers are absent.

Nolan Electrical December 2019

 Helped stock store room on delivery days and helped sell electrical utilities to customers.

Dawn Farms November 2018

- Worked with Microsoft Excel, rearranging/sorting data information of associated business companies.
- Researched lists of companies associated with Dawn Farms and searched for information about the companies that we may not have filed and filled in that information on an Excel sheet.

Skills and abilities

- Languages: Java, Python, C++, C, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, PHP.
- **IDEs and Editors**: Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio Codium, IntelliJ, PyCharm, Eclipse, Jupyter Notebook, Android Studio, GitHub, and willing to learn more where necessary.
- Data Science and Machine Learning: Jupyter Notebook, Jinja, Flask, PythonAnywhere, Anvil
- Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, SQLite, MariaDB,
- Libraries / Frameworks: Django, Flask, Bootstrap, Docker NumPy, Matplotlib, Node.js, Express.js
- Version Control Systems: GitHub
- Familiar with a variety of different Machine Learning algorithms; working with different types of data from data collecting – cleaning – training, tuning and predicting.
- Ability to multitask where necessary, working on two or more different projects within the same timeline and being able to work productively and efficiently to meet deadlines.

Previous Projects

- (Python/Jupyter Notebook) Advanced Machine Learning Portfolio Expansion: A
 project that involved deepening the theoretical understanding and practical
 application of machine learning algorithms. This included creating and enhancing
 Jupyter notebooks for each algorithm, using new datasets, fine-tuning algorithm
 parameters, and deploying serialized models through web applications, with detailed
 logs documenting the modifications and their impacts on model performance.
- (C++) A Predator-Prey simulation is a model designed to replicate the dynamics between two key ecological roles: predators and prey. This simulation illustrates the interactions and relationships that occur in ecosystems where one species hunts and consumes another for sustenance, creating a wave-like environment between the two.
- (Java) A multi-choice quiz game application. Accessible through a mobile application where a person can choose a series of quiz-topic questions they wish to play and filter the questions to their preference between categories and difficulty.
- (HTML/CSS/JS) Created and deployed a personal portfolio containing into about myself, skills, projects and more
- (Python, HTML, CSS) Built a multi-page web application using Flask and Jinja2 with VS-Code which provides a website with pages that include details about myself, my interests, a page about specific computing technologies, and a form page where users can leave a review or a question which is saved and stored on a database using MySQL. Used Pytest to write tests to ensure the code coverage and database code was as close to 100% as it could get.

Other samples of code with Java, JavaScript, Python, C++, and more are available on GitHub.

Skills and Hobbies

Outside of college/work time, I enjoy playing and watching games and sports. I am currently playing rugby union for County Carlow and SETU Carlow. I previously played rugby league at an international level for 3 years where we played teams like England, Scotland, Wales, Italy, and more. I enjoy watching both rugby and football matches. I enjoy working on software projects outside of class, building a Portfolio website and a Trivia Quiz game, I also enjoy watching YouTube videos of game developers for big game franchises about how they developed games over the years.

References

Khan Habib, Manager, Top Oil Staplestown Road, Carlow, 089-964-0251 Ian Cullen, Regional Sales Director, Dawn Farms, Kildare, 087-970-7992

Susan Hennessy, Finance Lead, Kilkenny, 086-878-6506